Guide to the Philip Agee Papers TAM.517
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
- Series VIII, Writings
  - Subseries VIII-F, Writings About Agee
    - Miscellaneous Topics (Greek, with some Translations), 1985 (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Miscellaneous Topics (Italian), 1975-1979 (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - Miscellaneous Topics (Norwegian), 1979-1984 (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - Miscellaneous Topics (Portuguese), 1974-1979 (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - Miscellaneous Topics (Spanish), 1974-1994, 2000 (Box 19, Folder 25)
    - Miscellaneous Topics (Spanish), 1974-1989 (Box 19, Folder 26)
    - Morales, Ricardo; Death, Role in Tracking Mr. Agee, Feb 10, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 27)
    - NBC's Connection to Agee, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 28)
    - "On Company Business" Documentary about the CIA (includes Agee), 1980 (Box 19, Folder 29)
    - Press Releases on Agee, undated (Box 19, Folder 30)
    - Senator Howard Baker's Report on "On Western Hemisphere Flap" and Philip Agee, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 31)
    - Tsantes, George; Assassination; Allegations against Philip Agee, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 32)
    - Welch, Richard; CIA Agent Exposed in Counterspy (Photocopies), 1978 (Box 19, Folder 33)
    - Welch, Richard; CIA Agent Exposed in Counterspy (Originals), 1975-1986 (Box 19, Folder 34)
  - Subseries VIII-G, Writings By Others
    - Anonymous: "The American Commitment to Democracy-A Bipartisan Approach" (Issued by the Democracy Program), Nov 30, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 35)
    - Anonymous: Fragment on Author's Grandmother (Locale: San Francisco), undated (Box 19, Folder 36)
    - Anonymous: "La CIA y Sus Objetiuos-Como Trabaja la Contrarevolucion", 1980 (Box 19, Folder 37)
    - Brandt, Daniel: "From the Pentagon to the Net-Informal and Disinformation", Oct 1995-Dec 1995 (Box 19, Folder 38)
    - Cohen, Sylvester: History of Colonial Revolutions in Portuguese Africa (Dissertation Excerpts), May 1977 (Box 19, Folder 39)
    - Ellsberg, Daniel: "US First Use of Threats and the Construction of Instability," "For Gary Snyder's 60th Birthday-The First Time We Met," "Randy Kehler: Haverford, August 1969," and Janaki: Princeton, April, 1968", undated, 1986-1989 (Box 19, Folder 40)
    - Katz, Richard: "Arrested in Grenada" (Play), 1987 (Box 19, Folder 41)
    - Kende, Istvan: Hungarian Economist, Articles on European Wars, 1971-1982 (Box 19, Folder 42)
    - Khrushchev, Nikita: Secret Tapes, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 43)
    - Knowles, James C.: "The Rockefeller Financial Group", 1973 (Box 19, Folder 44)
    - Livingstone, Neil C.: "Fighting Terrorism and 'Dirty Little Wars'", 1984 (Box 19, Folder 45)
    - Marshall, Jonathan: "Brief Notes on the Political Importance of Secret Societies," Part I and II, undated (Box 19, Folder 46)
    - Morley, Morris and Steven Smith; "Destabilizing the Periphery: US Policy and the CIA in Chile", 1975 (Box 19, Folder 47)
    - Neumaier, John J.,: Opinion Column in "Sunday Freeman", 1986-1989 (Box 19, Folder 48)
    - Peirats, Papik: "La CIA por Dentro, Part I, II, and III." [An Overview of the CIA Part I, II, and III] (Spanish), 1977 (Box 19, Folder 49)
    - Reimann, Elisabeth: Historia de Moises (Photocopy), 1985 (Box 19, Folder 50)
    - Roberts, Adam; "The CIA: Reform is Not Enough", Apr 15, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 51)
    - Roth, Brad R.; "The First Amendment in the Foreign Affairs Realm: "Domesticating the Restrictions on Citizen Participation", 1993 (Box 19, Folder 52)
    - Sahl, Mort: "Heartland" (Typescript), 1976 (Box 19, Folder 53)
    - Sweeney, Cynthia: "CIA and CWA," Published by Local, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 54)
    - Waghelstein, John D., US Army Colonel: "Post-Vietnam Counterinsurgency Doctrine", Apr 1982 (Box 19, Folder 55)
    - Whitman, David: "The Press and the Neutron Bomb", 1983 (Box 19, Folder 56)
    - Wilkinson, J.B.: United States Foreign Policy and Indonesia, Chapter 2: "1950-1955", undated (Box 19, Folder 57)
- Series IX, Oversized Clippings About Agee, 1975-1980
  Series IX, Oversized Clippings About Agee (1975-1980), contains clippings about Agee, or for events or activities involving Agee, some freestanding, some within issues of various newspapers and periodicals. Some of these are of graphic interest.
  - Clippings, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, Jan 1977-Aug 1977 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, Sep 1977 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 1979-1980 (Box 20, Folder 4)
- Series X, Audiocassettes and Computer Discs (Box 21)
  Series X, Audiocassettes and Computer Discs (undated) contains twelve audiocassettes from an untitled and undated seminar on various aspects of U.S. Intelligence activities, probably given in Europe, possibly in Germany, in the latter 1990s or early 2000s, and two 3 inch computer discs containing lectures about Cuba and U.S. Intelligence activities directed against Cuba.
  - Seminar (untitled): Audiocassette# 0D, undated (Box 21, Cassette 1)
  - Seminar (untitled): Audiocassette# 1D, undated (Box 21, Cassette 2)
  - Seminar (untitled): Audiocassette# 2, undated (Box 21, Cassette 3)
  - Seminar (untitled): Audiocassette# 2A, undated (Box 21, Cassette 4)
  - Seminar (untitled): Audiocassette# 2D (Eur. Rechte), undated (Box 21, Cassette 5)
  - Seminar (untitled): Audiocassette# 3, undated (Box 21, Cassette 6)
  - Seminar (untitled): Audiocassette# 3D (URSRUNGE K.K.), unddated (Box 21, Cassette 7)
  - Seminar (untitled): Audiocassette# 5, undated (Box 21, Cassette 8)
  - Seminar (untitled): Audiocassette# 6, undated (Box 21, Cd 9)
  - Seminar (untitled): Audiocassette# 7A, undated (Box 21, Cassette 10)
  - Seminar (untitled): Audiocassette# 8 (Iran), undated (Box 221, Cassette 11, Box 21)
  - Seminar (untitled): Audiocassette# 9 (Guatemala), undated (Box 21, Cassette 12)
  - CIA's War against Cuba and Cuba's Response (German Translation): Computer disc, 3 inch, undated (Box 21, Disk 1, Box 221)
  - Cuba Speech/Lecture (Deutsch Version): Computer disc, 3 inch (Box 21, Disk 2)
- Series XI, Photographs, 1976-1986, 2000 (Box A005)
  This series contains photographs of Agee at speaking events, interviews, and other events. There are a significant amount of photographs from the Agee and Hosenball demonstrations. In 1977, Agee and Mark Hosenball, a journalist, were deported from the United Kingdom for revealing state secrets.
  Other subjects of the photographs include Phillip Noel-Baker, Prime Minister of Grenada Maurice Bishop, Regina Fischer, Jo Richardson, Governor of California Jerry Brown, Fidel Castro, Ricardo Alarcón and others.
  Most of the photographs were taken by Andrew Wiard.